American Institute of Architects Records
American Institute of Architects Records
1922-1988
American Institute of Architects.
81 linear ft.
CNY chapter records, committee material on professional practice, conduct, and disciplinary material, printed material, more.
2677424
Biographical History
Based in Washington, D.C., the AIA has been the leading professional membership association for licensed architects, emerging professionals, and allied partners since 1857. The AIA serves as the voice of the architecture profession and the resource for its members, through advocacy, information, and community. [Taken from the AIA website, http://www.aia.org/about/index.htm.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The American Institute of Architects Records consists of office files, financial files, official records, membership information, publications, films, audiotapes, photographs, exhibit memorabilia, and architectural drawings
Arrangement of the Collection
Most series are arranged alphabetically by name, type, or title.
Related Material
has the papers of many notable architects, inluding Marcel Breuer, Pietro Belluschi, William Lescaze, and many more. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Architects; American Institute of Architects.; Architecture -- New York (State); Architectural drawings (visual works); Audiocassettes.; Film reels.; Minutes (administrative records); Newsletters.; Photographs.; Reports.; Sound recordings.; Architects.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Additional access restrictions lifted in 2008.
Acquisition Information
Gift of American Institute of Architects, 1971, 1988.
CNYAIA newsletters, gift of Ohio History Connection, 2017.
Inventory
- Architectural drawings
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 1)
  - Miscellaneous, most are of Syracuse buildings; 74 drawings
- Board of directors
  - Minutes, 1922-1980 (Box 1)
- Exhibit material
  - Plaques (Box 15)
  - Exhibit photographs (Box 15)
  - Other exhibit items (Box 15)
- Films and audiotapes
  - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
- Financial material
  - General
    - Ledgers (Box 4)
    - Dues (Box 4)
  - Treasurer's files
    - Deni, Gerald S., 1974-1976 (Box 4)
    - Hares, Francis, 1965-1967 (Box 4)
    - Houseworth, John, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Hueber, Paul, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
    - King, Bruce, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Lafferty, Richard T., 1979 (Box 5)
    - Pallone, Richard, 1979 (Box 5)
    - Secor, Robert, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
    - Spina, Dennis, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Teitsch, John, 1974-1975 (Box 5)
  - Treasurer's reports
    - Miscellaneous, 1932-1977; 10 folders (Box 5)
- Official records
  - Bylaws (Box 6)
  - Incorporation papers (Box 6)
  - Minutes, 1966-1972; 1979-1981,; 1984-1985,; undated; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Membership files
    - Categories (Box 7)
    - Lists (Box 7)
    - Printed directories (Box 7)
- Office files
  - Councils, committees, commissions, and task forces
    - A-L (Box 8)
    - L-S (Box 9)
  - Subject files
    - AIA National, 1970-1978 (Box 2)
  - General subject files
    - A-N, 1952-1986 (Box 2)
    - N-W, 1958-1978 (Box 3)
- Members
  - A-W (Box 10)
  - Ethics committee (Box 10)
- Photographs
  - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
- Publications
  - New York State Association of Architects (Box 7)
  - National American Institute of Architects (Box 7)
  - Newsletters, CNYAIA, 1982 (Box 7)
    Gift of Ohio History Connection, 2017
  - Straight Edge newsletter, 1948-1978; 6 folders (Box 11)
  - CNYAIA Newsletter, 1981-1988 (Box 11)
  - Camera ready copy (to be culled: photos pulled, identified, and retained, remainder discarded) (Box 12)
- Seminars, conventions and symposia
  - Miscellaneous (Box 12)